const quizQuestions19en = [{
    question:"In TIG welding with argon shielding, the 6 mm long arc has a voltage of 18 V. What will the voltage be if the arc is reduced to 5 mm without changing the current?",
    answers: ["Around 14 V.",
    "Around 15 V.",
    "Around 16 V.",
    "Around 17 V."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the physical effects on which High Frequency (HF) welding is based?",
    answers: ["Piezoelectric effect, which is the ability of some metals to generate heat in response to mechanical pressure.",
    "Peltier effect, which is the generation of heat at the junction of two conductors subjected to an electrical voltage.",
    "\"\"\"Proximity effect\"\" is the tendency of high frequency current to concentrate in the nearest adjacent regions in reverse conductors.\"",
    "Seebeck effect, which is the generation of a potential difference (electrical voltage) between two conductors when they are subjected to a high frequency magnetic field."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the fundamentals of explosion welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["there is a need to preheat the sheets, due to their large dimensions;",
    "The diffusion effect is small or non-existent, because of a short duration of the process.",
    "There is a need to preheat the plates, to speed up the effect of interlocking resulting from the undulations of the interface between the plates during the explosion.",
    "The used filler metal works similarly as in brazing/soldering, wetting the joint interface."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the fundamentals of explosion welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["there is a need to preheat the sheets, due to their large dimensions;",
    "There is a need to preheat the plates, to speed up the effect of interlocking resulting from the undulations of the interface between the plates during the explosion.",
    "The joining is metallurgical, combined with mechanical interlocking resulting from the undulations of the interface between the sheets.",
    "The used filler metal works similarly as in brazing/soldering, wetting the joint interface."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct for the Laser Directed Energy Deposition (L-DED) process with powder addition?",
    answers: ["When increasing the powder feed rate, keeping the other parameters unchanged, the roughness decreases.",
    "When increasing the power, keeping the other parameters unchanged, the roughness increases.",
    "When decreasing the scanning speed, keeping the other parameters unchanged, the roughness decreases.",
    "By reducing the powder feed rate, keeping the other parameters unchanged, the roughness increases."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Both wire and powder can be used in the Laser Directed Energy Deposition (L-DED) process. What is an advantage of using powder?",
    answers: ["High robustness of the deposition process.",
    "Ease of storage.",
    "High deposition efficiency.",
    "Low cost of powder."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Both wire and powder can be used in the Laser Directed Energy Deposition (L-DED) process. What is a disadvantage of using wire?",
    answers: ["Limited range of possible chemical compositions of the filler metal.",
    "Lower deposition rate.",
    "High cost of wire.",
    "Low deposition efficiency."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment of the resistance spot welding parameters, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The higher the voltage, the larger the spot diameter.",
    "Radiused tip electrodes cannot be used, as the spot would be too small.",
    "A solution for welding sheets of different thickness is to use electrodes with different diameters (larger on the side of the thicker sheet).",
    "A solution for welding sheets of different thicknesses is to use electrodes with different diameters (smaller on the side of the thicker sheet)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding specific versions of the Plasma Welding Process, the following statement is true.",
    answers: ["The Plasma-MIG process has higher tolerance for gap and joint misalignment than other processes with the same deposition capacity or welding speed.",
    "The powder plasma arc welding (PPAW) process uses a non-transferred arc, which makes it more suitable for surfacing.",
    "The powder plasma arc welding (PPAW) process is never used for bevelled groove welds.",
    "The Plasma-MIG process has lower tolerance for gap and joint misalignment than other processes with the same deposition capacity or welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding specific versions of the Plasma Welding Process, the following statement is true.",
    answers: ["The powder plasma arc welding (PPAW) process uses a non-transferred arc, which makes it more suitable for surfacing.",
    "The main factors that limit the use of plasma welding with powder addition are a high cost of equipment (torches and powder feeders) and powders, as well as the need for more specialized operators.",
    "The powder plasma arc welding (PPAW) process is never used for bevelled groove welds.",
    "The Plasma-MIG process has lower tolerance for gap and joint misalignment than other processes with the same deposition capacity or welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding with alternating current, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The current level in the positive polarity is higher than in the negative one to maintain the same melting rate in both polarities.",
    "The current level in the positive polarity is lower than in the negative one to maintain the same melting rate in both polarities.",
    "Arc stability is low, so this process is only used for maintenance.",
    "Process of a very high deposition rate (compatible with the Double Wire MIG), due to the negative polarity contribution."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true statement about the generation and transfer of heat in the arc:",
    answers: ["Positive electrode polarity is used in processes with consumable electrodes to increase their melting rate, as the anodic region generates more heat than the cathodic region.",
    "Not always the higher the arc voltage, the greater the heat input.",
    "The higher the arc voltage, for the same current, the greater the thermal efficiency of the arc.",
    "The thermal efficiency of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is higher than that of MIG/MAG welding with short-circuit transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true statement about the generation and transfer of heat in the arc:",
    answers: ["Positive electrode polarity is used in processes with consumable electrodes to increase their melting rate, as the anodic region generates more heat than the cathodic region.",
    "The higher the arc voltage, for the same current, the greater the thermal efficiency of the arc.",
    "If the cathode material is refractory (tungsten), heating may be sufficient for thermionic emission, which is the main electron emission mechanism for arcs with non-consumable electrodes (hot cathode).",
    "The thermal efficiency of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is higher than that of welding with short-circuit mode."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["In the arc SW process, in general, the workpiece is connected to the positive pole and the stud to the negative pole, except for aluminium, where it is inverted.",
    "There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why does solid wire welding (MIG/MAG) typically produce a more convex bead compared to tubular electrode welding (FCAW) using the same welding current?",
    answers: ["The MIG/MAG process has a hotter and shorter arc.",
    "Solid wire offers a higher deposition rate (since the tubular electrode has a tube-like cross-section): more metal is deposited, the more convex the bead becomes.",
    "The flux within the tubular electrode helps to minimize the surface tension between the liquid metal and the weld pool.",
    "The metal deposited by the solid wire has a different chemical composition, which normally results in a low wettability compared to that of a similar tubular electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the EBW process, the penetration of electrons into the base material will depend on:",
    answers: ["Chemical composition of the electron-emitting cathode material.",
    "Base metal surface condition.",
    "Welding parameters: acceleration voltage, beam spot size, beam current.",
    "Current type (DC or AC) and polarity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the EBW process, the penetration of electrons into the base material will depend on:",
    answers: ["Chemical composition of the electron-emitting cathode material.",
    "Base metal surface condition.",
    "Current type (DC or AC) and polarity.",
    "Thermo-physical properties of the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"You want to use additive manufacturing to perform a workpiece with gradually changing chemical composition. Which of these processes is most appropriate?",
    answers: ["MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding process.",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding process.",
    "Laser Directed Energy Deposition (L-DED) process with powder addition.",
    "Selective Laser Melting process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The presence of hydrogen in argon + hydrogen gas mixtures used for TIG/GTAW:",
    answers: ["can reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding aluminium;",
    "may allow you to increase the welding speed;",
    "can reduce porosity in welding carbon steels;",
    "can reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the gases is the heaviest?",
    answers: ["Methane.",
    "Butane.",
    "Acetylene.",
    "Carbon dioxide."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the gases is the least heavy?",
    answers: ["Methane.",
    "Butane.",
    "Acetylene.",
    "Carbon dioxide."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"The presence of hydrogen in argon + hydrogen gas mixtures used for GTAW/TIG welding:",
    answers: ["can reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding aluminium;",
    "may allow you to increase the welding speed;",
    "can reduce porosity in welding carbon steels;",
    "can reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weld metal of two cast iron pieces will have:",
    answers: ["higher tensile strength than the base metal;",
    "higher ductility than the base metal;",
    "higher hardness than the base metal;",
    "less ductility than the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When using copper-based covered electrodes for cast iron, the minimum interpass temperature should be of:",
    answers: ["150 ºC;",
    "205 °C;",
    "350 °C;",
    "450 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following procedures should be used when welding fine grained steels?",
    answers: ["Post weld heating at 250 °C, just after welding for, at least, 48 h, to force the H2 to go out of the weld metal.",
    "Post weld heating at 250 °C, just after welding for 2 h, to reduce the risk of martensite formation in the weld metal.",
    "Weld the root with a lower strength consumable, and then, after the weld is finished, the root must be removed by gouging and a back weld must be made.",
    "Post weld heating of fine-grained steels is not recommended to prevent possible grain size growth."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding defects of the materials crystal lattice:",
    answers: ["Punctual defects of the crystals are of no practical importance because of their small dimensions;",
    "Simple dislocations, edge dislocations, and helix dislocations are only important to justify why the actual strength of the crystals is less than their theoretical strength;",
    "Dislocations are defects that cannot be generated by other existing dislocations;",
    "The grain boundaries are considered imperfections because they separate regions of different crystalline orientations (i.e. grains)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding defects of the materials crystal lattice:",
    answers: ["Punctual defects of the crystals are of no practical importance because of their small dimensions;",
    "Simple dislocations, edge dislocations, and helix dislocations are only important to justify why the actual strength of the crystals is less than their theoretical strength;",
    "Dislocations are defects that can be generated by other existing dislocations, through the mechanism proposed by Frank and Read, usually called the Frank-Read Source;",
    "The grain contours are not considered being imperfections because they only separate crystals of different orientations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Assinale a alternativa correta para evitar a corrosão intergranular dos aços inoxidáveis austeníticos:",
    answers: ["Using as much heat as possible, in order to dissolve the chromium carbides;",
    "Using low carbon base and filler metal (< 0.03%);",
    "Using base and filler metal stabilized with aluminium and/or vanadium;",
    "Heating the material in the range of 400 to 800 °C and cooling slowly."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Assinale a alternativa correta para evitar a corrosão intergranular dos aços inoxidáveis austeníticos:",
    answers: ["Using as much heat as possible, in order to dissolve the chromium carbides;",
    "Using low carbon base and filler metal (< 0.3%);",
    "Using base and filler metal stabilized with titanium and/or niobium;",
    "Heating the material in the range of 400 to 800 °C and cooling slowly."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding creep phenomenon in metallic materials, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In general, ferritic stainless steels have a higher creep resistance than austenitic stainless steels because the former have a crystal lattice with lower atomic diffusivity;",
    "At high temperatures, one of the main creep mechanisms is intergranular slipping. In this condition, coarse-grained steels tend to have a higher creep resistance.",
    "The main creep mechanism is intergranular slipping. Thus, fine-grained steels tend to have a higher creep resistance.",
    "The creep rate is minimal at the primary creep phase, due to a balance between strain hardening and recovery processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nickel alloys can be classified into:",
    answers: ["Solid solution and cold work hardened alloys;",
    "Solid solution and precipitation hardened alloys;",
    "Transformable alloys and peritectic alloys;",
    "Transformable alloys and non-transformable alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In the TIG welding of nickel alloys one must:",
    answers: ["use shielding gas with the addition of oxygen to increase arc stability;",
    "promote efficient cleaning of joint edges with mechanical and chemical methods;",
    "use shielding gas with the addition of Nitrogen to form beneficial nitrides in the weld metal;",
    "use narrower groove angles (40 - 60 degrees) to reduce angular distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct statement regarding phase transformations:",
    answers: ["The phase transformations begin with the appearance of very small particles of a new phase, which grow until the transformation is complete;",
    "The growth of new particles is independent of the ratio of surface energy to volume energy;",
    "Every particle with a smaller radius than the critical one tends to re-dissolve, and every particle with a radius greater than the critical one tends to decrease, since the critical radius is unique to each material;",
    "Anything that influences the increase in the critical radius increases the nucleation rate and reduces the grain size."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the most satisfactory welding repair method for malleable cast iron?",
    answers: ["MMA (SMAW) welding.",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW).",
    "Oxy-acetylene braze welding (because of a relatively low temperature used)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements would you add to steel to ensure red-hardness?",
    answers: ["Niobium.",
    "Manganese.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Cobalt."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Zirconium and its commercial alloys are readily welded using the processes and procedure commonly adopted for welding:",
    answers: ["copper;",
    "aluminium;",
    "titanium;",
    "ferritic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cu-Ni alloys can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["solid solution;",
    "grain refining;",
    "aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cu-Zn copper alloys (brasses) can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["cold deformation (hardening);",
    "grain refining;",
    "aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper beryllium alloys can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "grain refining;",
    "cold deformation (hardening);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with regard to welding aluminium and its alloys:",
    answers: ["Fusion welding causes a reduction in joint strength in both treatable and non-heat-treatable aluminium alloys.",
    "Fusion welding of aluminium alloys causes a degradation of the mechanical strength of the molten metal of the joint, but increases the strength of the HAZ due to recrystallization.",
    "The weld regions of non-heat-treatable alloys have low ductility compared to the base metal.",
    "The popularity of high-strength alloys, belonging to the 5XXX series in welded structures, occurs because they have high resistance in the tempering condition followed by annealing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding low-carbon or low-alloy structural steel to austenitic stainless steel using austenitic stainless filler metal, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["preheating is mandatory to avoid H2 cracking in ferritic steel;",
    "the Schaeffler diagram is useful for predicting the structure resulting from dissimilar welds only when filler metal is used;",
    "the presence of delta ferrite in the fusion zone favours the formation of a sigma phase if the joint works at high temperatures;",
    "austenitic stainless filler metal (very ductile!) reduces the risk of hot cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding low-carbon or low-alloy structural steel to austenitic stainless steel using austenitic stainless filler metal, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["preheating is mandatory to avoid H2 cracking in ferritic steel;",
    "the Schaeffler diagram is useful for predicting the structure resulting from dissimilar welds only when filler metal is used;",
    "preheating can be used to avoid embrittlement of the HAZ in ferritic steel;",
    "austenitic stainless filler metal (very ductile!) reduces the risk of hot cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Mn.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["P.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Si.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Sn.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["As.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["P.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Sb.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Sn.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Coating thickness of hot dip zinc coating is about:",
    answers: ["1 micron;",
    "5 microns;",
    "60 microns;",
    "300 microns."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How can spherical graphite be formed in cast iron?",
    answers: ["By adding Si.",
    "By adding Mg + Ce.",
    "By alloying with aluminium.",
    "By fast cooling during solidification."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which one of the physical characteristics mentioned below might cause problems in case of dissimilar welding of ferritic with austenitic steels?",
    answers: ["The longitudinal elasticity modulus.",
    "The transverse elasticity modulus.",
    "The thermal conductivity coefficient.",
    "The linear expansion coefficient."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The results of welded joint testing by fracture mechanics can be used:",
    answers: ["for determination of component cross-sections of welded structure projects;",
    "for assessment of fitness to purpose of welded structures including information on welding imperfections;",
    "as values required by technical inspection societies;",
    "as values required by future users of steel constructions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following gases possesses of the highest heating value (kJ/m3)?",
    answers: ["Acetylene.",
    "Propane.",
    "Natural gas.",
    "LPG."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ultimate strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The elongation of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property, therefore its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ultimate strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The yield strength of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ultimate strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The elongation of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The yield strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The ultimate strength of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on sample size.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"Regarding the fatigue resistance of welded structures, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the calculation rules of most standards for dimensioning welded structures in relation to fatigue strength are based on S-N curves;",
    "the fatigue resistance of welded joints is independent of the static strength of the material;",
    "the global fatigue resistance of metallic structures is not limited by the fatigue strength of its welded joints;",
    "the effect of average fluctuating stresses is considered by most steel structure design standards."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the stress concentration in workpieces, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The geometric coefficient of stress concentration takes into account the sensitivity of the material to the notch;",
    "The fatigue stress concentration coefficient is smaller than the corresponding stress concentration geometric coefficient;",
    "In general, higher strength steels are less sensitive to notch than more ductile steels;",
    "Joints built of high-carbon steels present geometric coefficients of stress concentration higher than the same joints built of low-carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About Coulomb's and von Mises' theories of material resistance, it is possible to say:",
    answers: ["Both theories explain the failure of a brittle material;",
    "Both theories explain the failure of a ductile material;",
    "Mohr Coulomb's theory better explains the failure of a brittle material, while Von Mises' theory - a ductile material.",
    "Mohr Coulomb's theory better explains the failure of a ductile material, while Von Mises' theory - a brittle material;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Palmgren-Miner rule calculates:",
    answers: ["the service life duration of a structure (in years);",
    "the number of cycles to failure at the average stress level;",
    "the number of cycles to failure at the maximum stress level;",
    "cumulative fatigue damage."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following assumptions is made when using the IIW formula to calculate the stress in a fillet weld?",
    answers: ["There are no internal stresses (i.e., residual stresses are neglected).",
    "The type of loading is taken into account.",
    "Stress concentrators (e.g., toes of the weld) are taken into consideration.",
    "The allowable stress is determined on the basis of the weld metal strength."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following assumptions is made when using the IIW formula to calculate the stress in a fillet weld?",
    answers: ["Stress concentrators (e.g., toes of the weld) are not taken into consideration.",
    "The type of loading is taken into account.",
    "Residual stresses are taken into consideration.",
    "The allowable stress is determined on the basis of the weld metal strength."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following assumptions is made when using the IIW formula to calculate the stress in a fillet weld?",
    answers: ["The allowable stress is determined on the basis of the parent metal strength.",
    "The type of loading is taken into account.",
    "Stress concentrators (e.g., toes of the weld) are taken into consideration.",
    "Residual stresses are taken into consideration."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The expression for \"\"Paris Law\"\" describing crack propagation for cyclic loading is:\"",
    answers: ["da/dN=Co(Ds)m;",
    "da/dN=Co(DK)m-1/m;",
    "da/dN=Com (DK);",
    "da/dN=Co(DK)m."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The small-scale yielding phenomenon is a subject of:",
    answers: ["the Bauschinger effect;",
    "the theory of St. Venant;",
    "the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM);",
    "the Mohr Coulomb's theory."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these NDT methods is characterized by the detection of a discontinuity due to its propagation?",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic ToFD.",
    "ACFM method.",
    "Eddy current test.",
    "Acoustic emission method."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding welding curtains, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Welding curtains must allow the arc light to pass from the inside to the outside, thus ensuring that people outside can observe the operator, preventing and remedying incidents.",
    "Welding curtains must be not transparent and black in colour to absorb all the light from the arc.",
    "Ideal welding curtains should prevent ultraviolet rays and absorb blue light (disturbing to the eyes) but allow light perceived as yellow-orange to pass through.",
    "Ideal curtains should allow only ultraviolet and infrared light to pass through and absorb all visible light."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"There is a repaired weld on a carbon steel sheet and the deposited material is non-magnetic. In this case the Magnetic Particle inspection will:",
    answers: ["cause a magnetization with high retentivity in the weld region.",
    "cause false indications in the transition region between the base metal and the deposited metal.",
    "probably detect transverse cracks in the transition region.",
    "not cause any indication in the weld transition region."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative regarding the dimensioning of discontinuities in the Ultrasonic testing.",
    answers: ["The 6 dB drop technique is used both to measure large discontinuities in sheets (double lamination) and also to measure the length of small reflectors in welds.",
    "The 6 dB drop technique is used to measure the thickness of the discontinuity.",
    "The 6 dB drop technique is only used to determine the size of the discontinuity in flat sheets (double lamination).",
    "The 6 dB technique is only used with angled heads."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the application of rebars (reinforcing steel bars) in civil construction, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["According to ISO 17660, the recommended welding processes for welding rebars are: 111, 135, 21 and 441;",
    "As per ISO 17660, fillet welds are not applicable to rebars;",
    "MIG/MAG welding cannot be used to weld rebars in the field, as this process cannot be carried out in the presence of winds.",
    "The weldability of rebars depends on its chemical composition and the manufacturing process (controlled cooling)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the application of rebars (reinforcing steel bars) in civil construction, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["According to ISO 17660, the recommended welding processes for welding rebars are: 111, 135, 21 and 441;",
    "As per ISO 17660, fillet welds are not applicable to rebars;",
    "MIG/MAG welding cannot be used to weld rebars in the field, as this process cannot be carried out in the presence of winds.",
    "Welded joints in rebars are distinguished by ISO 17660 in terms of whether the welded joint is load-bearing or non-load-bearing. In the latter case the welded joint strength is not taken into account."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In your opinion, for which of the following cases the fitness for purpose concept may be used?",
    answers: ["Instead of S460 steel a S235 steel was used. The stresses in the structure are calculated on the basis of S460 steel. The client accepts the use of the fitness for purpose concept.",
    "The application standard does require quality class C (ISO 5817), but only quality class D is met. The stresses in the structure are on a low level. The client refuses the use of the fitness for purpose concept.\"",
    "Only the class D quality (ISO 5817) was reached instead of the required C. The stresses in the structure are low.",
    "Only the class D quality (ISO 5817) was reached instead of the required C. The stresses in the structure are high."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these alternatives describes the principle of measuring residual welding stresses by the Barkhausen Noise Technique?",
    answers: ["Measuring the propagation speed of electromagnetic noise in the material which (propagation speed) depends on the stress level in the material.",
    "Measuring the propagation speed of acoustic noise in the material which (propagation speed) depends on the stress level in the material.",
    "Measuring the attenuation of electromagnetic noise in the material which depends on the stress level in the material.",
    "Measuring the amplitude of the noises coming from the rapid growth of the similarly magnetically oriented area."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the non-destructive methods for measuring residual welding stresses is:",
    answers: ["Inspection by eddy currents.",
    "Barkhausen Noise Analysis (for ferromagnetic materials);",
    "Blind hole drilling technique;",
    "Sectioning method."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these questions does NOT need to be answered when the critical assessment of \"\"fitness for purpose\"\" is applied to a welded structure?\"",
    answers: ["What is the remaining strength of the structure as a function of accumulated damage?",
    "What measure should be taken to increase the quality of welded joints used in the construction in question?",
    "What is the extent of damage that can be tolerated in service (remaining service life)?",
    "What is the recommended inspection frequency/plan in order to avoid premature failure?"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these questions does NOT need to be answered when the critical assessment of \"\"fitness for purpose\"\" is applied to a welded structure?\"",
    answers: ["What is the remaining strength of the structure as a function of accumulated damage?",
    "What change should be introduced in the manufacturing process to eliminate the causes of revealed defects?",
    "What is the extent of damage that can be tolerated in service (remaining service life)?",
    "What is the damage progression rate until the structure operational limit is reached?"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these questions does NOT need to be answered when the critical assessment of \"\"fitness for purpose\"\" is applied to a welded structure?\"",
    answers: ["What is the damage progression rate until the structure operational limit is reached?",
    "What change should be introduced in the design of the welded structure so that the revealed defects do not develop again?",
    "What is the extent of damage that can be tolerated in service (remaining service life)?",
    "What is the recommended inspection frequency/plan in order to avoid premature failure?"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "The Kr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and local stress concentrations.",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of components with discontinuities that meet the quality criteria.",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity.",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a limiting condition, which could be expressed in terms of flaw size, applied stress, minimum required fracture toughness or some other parameter.",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The FAD vertical axis defines the load ratio Lr = P/Pu, where Pu denotes the limit load for the cracked component;",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "Secondary stresses (such as local welding residual stress) are self-balanced across the section thickness and may drive crack propagation, but not plastic collapse.",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of components with discontinuities that meet the quality criteria.",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "The Kr axis reflects the influence of both primary and secondary stresses, while the Lr axis primary stresses only. ",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"}]
    
;